（麦洁文、林蛟、龙铭恩）
Starring: Connie mak, lam kau, lung ming-yan,
（薛芷伦、林伟雄，领衔主演）
sit chi-lun, Jeffrey lam
（田丰、鲍汉林、 曾江）
tien feng, pau hon-lam, Kenneth tsang
（王霄、古正光、黄子扬）
Kelvin wong, koo jing-kwong, karel wong
（林康、金日龙、Robert Zajac）
lin kang, jing ri long, Robert zajac
（友情客串）
cameo role
（主题曲 「飞沙风中转」 ）
theme song: "Shifting sand revolving in the air"
（音乐作曲 ： 罗大佑，鲁世杰）
composer: Lo tayu, Richard lo
（填词 ：林振强， 罗大佑）
lyricist: Richard lam, lo tayu
（主唱：周润发， 罗大佑）
singer: Chow yun-fat, lo tayu
-爸爸  -阿祖
- Daddy. - Joe.
-今天乖不乖啊？  -乖
- Are you a good boy today? - Yes.
-有没有听妈妈的话？  -有啊
- Did you listen to your mom? - Yes.
挠你痒…
Kiding ypu...
老婆， 让他听吧
Dear, let him answer.
-喂，爷爷  -乖
- Hello, grandpa. - Good boy.
爷爷，你是不是找爸爸？
Grandpa, are you looking for daddy?
叫爸爸听电话
Ask your daddy to answer the phone.
爸爸…听电话
Daddy... your call.
真不知道你在跟爷爷说甚么
Don't know what you're talking to grandpa.
喂？
Hello?
爸，祝你年年有今日 ， 岁岁有今朝
Dad, happy birthday and many happy returns.
今天是你的生日
Today is your birthday.
我打了一整天电话给你，怎么没人接听
I've been calling you all day but couldn't reach you.
我刚刚有点事去了南丫岛谈
I've gone to lamma island.
肯定是去了虾叔那里  跟他拜年和打麻将吧
You must have gone to play mahjong with uncle ha.
爸，最近我跟朋友开了间地产公司
Dad, I've recently started an estate company with friends.
生意挺好
The business is good.
你们甚么时候回来？
When are you coming back?
等阿祖放假再回吧
Wait till Joe has holiday.
我很想念你们
I miss you.
爸，拜托你别做得这么辛苦了
Dad, please don't work so hard.
自己休息一下
Take some rest.
有空就过来看看我们吧
Come and visit us when you have time.
炳叔他们怎么样？
How are uncle ping and the rest?
帮我问候一下他们吧
Send them my regards.
爸，不跟你说了 ，我要和老婆吃饭了
Dad, I must hang up now. We're eating.
-就这样吧，再见  -再见
- That's all, bye bye. - Bye.
做甚么？你们做甚么？
What... what are you doing?
架生是拿来玩的吗？
You shouldn't play with these.
是出了事才拿来用的
They're for emergency use.
-收起来  -是…
- Put it away. - Yes...
都叫你不要拿出来玩的
I've told you not to play with it.
你们听着
Listen.
-今天我们龙头坤叔亲自带队， 明白吗？  -是
- Today, our boss uncle kwan will lead us. - Yes.
醒目一点， 随机应变
Be smart and alert.
知道了…
Got it...
（飞鹰堂）
Flying eagle hall
（洪兴）
Hung hing
（风调雨顺，恭贺新禧，合境平安）
good weather, happy new year, peace
-恭喜…  -恭喜…
- Congratulations... - Congratulations...
彼此彼此
Same to you.
-阿强  -坤叔
- Keung. - Uncle kwan.
帮我派利是给各位兄弟
Give these red packets to everyone.
-每人一封，不要派漏了  -是
- One for everybody, don't miss out. - Yes.
-谢谢，坤叔，进里面谈吧  -好
- Thanks, uncle kwan, let's go inside. - Okay.
这里有一份利是
Here are some red packets,
麻烦你派给各位兄弟吧
please distribute for me.
真是多谢你了
Thank you so much.
不用这么多
It's too much.
我看也差不多了
I think it's okay.
派漏了 ，就很不好意思
It's bad if I miss out anyone.
世侄，我们开门见山
Nephew, let's cut to the chase.
这个地盘以前本来是我和虾叔打下的
Uncle ha and I fought hard to get this territory.
你不应该怂恿你的手下
You shouldn't incite your men
暗中抢我的客户
to grab my clients.
何况我每个月都给你钱
Moreover, I do give you a share every month.
如果不够的话，可以开口
You can ask for more if it's not enough.
你这样做太不够江湖义气了
It's unreasonable that you did all that.
坤叔，你有没有查清楚？
Uncle kwan, have you checked?
我的兄弟怎么会这样做呢？
Why would my men do that?
现在说是你手下做的
We're giving you face...
已经给你一条金楼梯下台了
By saying your men did it.
你还装糊涂？
And you are still faking?
阿强，不要这么冲动
Keung, don't be impulsive.
坤叔
Uncle kwan.
以前虾老大跟你在南丫岛打天下
When uncle ha and you were at lamma island,
大家说好了是九二的
you agreed on the share.
不过虾老大有病，没有心情打理
But uncle ha is sick and can't take care of it.
收了你一笔钱就回乡下养病了
So he got a sum from you and retired.
但是你老人家连一声交待也没有
But you didn't even say a word about it.
随便出一份钱就算了 ，你当我是傻瓜？
You give us only a small share. Who do you think I am?
你们财源滚滚来， 四方来财
You make big money from all fields.
我们？只能看着
But we can only sit and watch.
时值新年，还回来说我抢你的客户？
New year is around the corner, and you said we grabbed your clients?
哪里有这么便宜的事？
How can you say that?
要冤枉别人，也要有赃有证吧
You must have evidence to back up your accusation.
这是证据
This is the evidence.
坤叔
Uncle kwan.
这些帐簿
Such ledgers...
我也可以弄三、五十本给你
I can make dozens of them for you.
虾毛
Little ha.
你有看过那些帐簿吗？
Have you seen these ledgers?
你现在抛这些帐簿出来，算甚么意思？
What's your intention of showing these ledgers?
你是甚么身分？何时轮到你说话？
Who do you think you are? Are you in any position to talk?
你又是甚么身分？
What are you then?
大家平起平坐，你吓我吗？
We're in the same position, are you scaring me?
-你以为我怕你？  -你又以为我怕你？
- You think I'm scared? - Neither am I scared of you.
阿强， 先坐下吧
Keung, sit down.
没有就最好，大家谈过就算了
It's good if you didn't do so, let's forget about it.
不过我不想以后再见到这样的事发生
But I don't want this to happen again.
好，坤叔，我尊重你老人家
Okay, uncle kwan, I respect you.
但是我怎么向我的手下交待？
But what am I going to say to my men?
你教教我吧
Please tell me.
打伤你的兄弟 ，我会赔偿医药费给他们
As I wounded your men, I'll compensate them.
你满意了吧？
Satisfied?
满意，坤叔都这样说了
Of course, since uncle kwan has said so,
想说不满意也不行
it must be okay.
但是
But...
不知道我 「飞鹰」 的招牌摆在哪里？
How can I keep the reputation of "flying eagle"?
打他是帮你们教导他
I taught him a lesson for you.
如果不是给你们社团面子， 早就杀了他
I would have killed him if it hadn't been for you.
你说话能不能注意一下主次？
Please remember who you are.
-这里是南丫岛  -怎么样？
- This is lamma island. - So?
-怎么样？  -别吵
- So? - Don't quarrel.
时值新年，为何吵吵闹闹？
Why quarrel during new year?
要开开心心才对
We should be happy.
好，坤叔，那现在我跟你说清楚
Okay, uncle kwan, let me make it clear.
以后在这里，你做你们的
From now on, you run your own business.
我做我们的 ，但是…
And I'll do ours, but...
你一定要封十万元利是给我的兄弟
You must give my men a red packet of 100,000 dollars.
甚么？
What?
现在是我老大给你机会
It's my boss who gives you a chance.
何时轮到你作主了？
Since when you have the rights to make decisions?
看看谁给谁机会
We'll see who gives chance.
打那老家伙
Beat that old man.
坤叔
Uncle kwan.
坤叔，走吧
Uncle kwan, let's go.
混蛋
Scum.
去死吧
Go to hell.
上啊…
Attack...
快拿架生…
Get the weapons...
坤叔，从窗口走
Uncle kwan, escape through the window.
坤叔，小心
Be careful, uncle kwan.
坤叔，小心啊
Uncle kwan, be careful.
坤叔，跳下去
Uncle kwan, jump.
-坤叔，你没事…  -阿胜，你不用说
- Uncle kwan, you'll be all right... - Shing, you don't have to say.
-你没事的 ，撑着  -你不用安慰我
- You'll be all right, hang on. - Don't have to console me.
阿豪回来，你叫他不要入社团
When ho is back, ask him not to join our gang.
不要替我报仇
And not to take revenge for me.
知道了 ，坤叔，我会照你的吩咐做的
I will, uncle kwan, I'll do as you say.
叫他回美国
Ask him to go back to the states.
小心点
Be careful.
小心
Careful.
-坤叔  -坤叔
- Uncle kwan. - Uncle kwan.
-开船…  -坤叔…
- Set sail... - Uncle kwan...
坤叔
Uncle kwan.
坤叔…
Uncle kwan...
-擦干头  -是
- Dry your hair. - Yes.
喂？
Hello?
-麻烦找李万豪先生  -你是谁？
- May I speak to Lee man ho? - Who's speaking?
-我是胜嫂  -甚么事？
- I'm shing's wife. - What's up?
阿胜有话跟你说，请你等一会
Shing has something to tell you, please hold on.
爸爸， 是谁打电话来？
Daddy, who's calling?
是谁打电话来？
Who's calling?
-阿豪，我是阿胜  -不要吵着爸爸
- Ho, this is shing. - Don't disturb your dad.
坤叔出了意外，他已经去世了
Uncle kwan met an accident and died.
我想你要马上赶回香港办理他的身后事
I think you should come back to Hong Kong for his funeral.
详细的事回来再说吧
I'll tell you everything when you are back.
-港哥  -港哥
- Brother Kong. - Brother Kong.
侯王道皱皮那笔数解决了 ，你数数
I've collected the debt from creasy, please count.
他肯给了吗？
He paid?
一说你的名字就马上给了
He paid promptly once I mentioned your name.
做得好，拿去用吧
Well done, take it.
谢谢港哥
Thanks, brother Kong.
以后知道怎么做了吧？
You know what to do next time?
-知道  -好
- Yes. - Good.
-喂，你们  -老大
- Hey, you two. - Boss.
你们两个是怎么回事？
What are you two doing?
今天是我们龙头办丧事
It's our leader's funeral today.
你们穿红戴绿做甚么？
Why are you wearing bright colors?
胜哥，不要这么生气了
Brother shing, don't be angry.
-还不快去换衣服  -是…
Go and change your clothes. Yes...
砂煲仔， 穿得真光鲜
Claypot, you're looking smart.
最近在哪里混？
Where have you been recently?
不要没大没小的
Don't be rude.
砂煲仔是你叫的吗？
How dare you address him as claypot?
砂煲哥现在是我们广香堂的坐馆
Brother claypot is now the head of kwong hiong hall.
不要乱拉关系
Know your place.
不要理他，走吧
Just ignore him, let's go.
呸
Darn it.
-港哥，他是谁？  -混蛋
- Brother Kong, who is he? - A scum.
以前跟我一起混的
We used to work together.
现在发迹了就装模作样
Now that he becomes successful, he thinks he's better.
看你能威风多久
I'll see how far you can go.
-真是可恶  -阿港
- What a jerk. - Kong.
-甚么事？  -没甚么 ，收了点尾数
- What's the matter? - Nothing, I've collected the balance amount.
你今天不要惹麻烦
Don't make trouble today.
知道了
Got it.
来，老爸，拿去买东西吃吧
Dad, take it and buy some food to eat.
-看紧一点，知道吗？  -知道了
- Keep an eye out, got it? - Got it.
（李府治丧）
Funeral at Lee's
标哥，不好意思
I'm sorry, brother bi...
前面太多车，塞住了
We're held up by traffic.
大哥
Boss.
对面那混蛋在拍照
The guy opposite is taking photos of us.
你怕了吗？
Are you scared?
我在警局的身家比电话簿还要厚
I've got many records at the police station.
出来混就不要怕他们 ， 当他们不存在
Don't be afraid, just ignore them.
（义薄云天）
Righteousness
一鞠躬
First bow.
再鞠躬
Second bow.
三鞠躬
Last bow.
家属谢礼
Gratitude from the family.
阿炳
Ping.
坤哥的儿子吗？
Is he brother kwan's son?
你认不出他了？
Don't you recognize him?
标哥，他就是万豪
Brother biu, he's man ho.
刚刚从美国回来
He's just returned from the states.
这是标叔，从小看着你长大
This is uncle biu, he's known you since you were small.
-标叔  -节哀顺变
- Uncle biu. - My condolences.
等等，标哥
Wait, brother bi...
他还是个孩子，甚么都不懂
He's only a child, he knows nothing.
头发都还没干，过去那边坐好吗？
Your hair's still wet, let's sit over there, okay?
来吧
Come on.
一鞠躬
First bow.
再鞠躬…
Second bow...
-老大，看来坤叔的儿子真的没甚么本事  -三鞠躬
- Boss, uncle kwan's son seem incompetent. - Third bow.
-家属谢礼  -我看未必
- Gratitude from the family. - It's hard to say.
扮猪吃老虎而已
He might be pretending.
很简单
That's simple.
随便找几个手下试试他就知道了
Send our men to test him and we'll know.
对吧？
Right?
-明天找几个手下跟着他  -是
- Send some men to follow him tomorrow. - Yes.
-有机会就试试他  -好，没问题
- Test him if there's a chance. - Sure.
一鞠躬
First bow.
再鞠躬
Second bow.
三鞠躬
Last bow.
家属谢礼
Gratitude from the family.
妈妈 ，甚么时候能走呀？我很累
Mom, when can we leave? I'm tired.
再坐一会吧
Stay a little longer.
不行
No.
不要不听话
Don't misbehave.
-阿祖，你做甚么？  -戴着它吧
- Joe, what are you doing? - Put it on.
戴上吧
Put it on.
箍着头很不舒服
It's uncomfortable with this tied on.
-戴上它吧  -乖点
- Put it on. - Be good.
戴上它
Put it on!
你为何那么大声喝他？
Why are you shouting at him?
-小孩子不懂的  -很快了 ，不要哭吧
- He's just a kid. - It's almost done, don't cry.
阿豪，不要这样，小孩子是这样的
Ho, don't be like this, he's just a kid.
不要哭了
Don't cry.
算了
Forget it.
我认为一定要推举阿豪才可以
I think we must elect ho.
如果大家认为阿豪可以，就这样决定吧
If everyone thinks ho is capable, we'll do just that.
坤叔临死之前说过，要让万豪回美国
But it's uncle kwan's will to ask man ho to go back to the states.
是，坤叔是这样说过
Yes, uncle kwan said that before.
但是我们洪兴如果没有坐馆
But if hung hing has no leader,
迟早会变成一盘散沙
it'll soon split up.
是啊，如果不推举阿豪
Right, if it's not ho,
那谁来做？你说吧
who will it be then? Tell me.
我们不要争执了 ，不如过去问问阿豪吧
Let's not argue, we shall ask ho.
好…
Yeah...
阿豪，我们想选你为办事人
Ho, we want you to be our leader.
你认为如何？
What do you think?
炳叔
Uncle ping.
你也知道我当初不喜欢我爸做社团的事
You've always known I didn't approve of my father working for the society.
我才去美国读书
That's why I went to study in the states.
总之，以后社团的事
Anything related to the society,
你不要算上我，我也不想理
don't count me in, I'll never lay an eye on it.
做完了爸爸的头七，我就回美国了
I'll return to the states after the funeral.
阿豪，那你爸爸剩下那么多物业
Ho, how about the estates...
由谁打理？
Your dad left behind?
还有，如果一个社团没有办事人
Moreover, if a society has no leader,
很快就会散掉
it'll soon collapse.
胜哥
Brother shing.
我爸的物业一向都是由你们打理
You've been taking care of my dad's properties.
应该由你们管理比较好
I think it's better that you take charge of them.
不过…
But...
炳叔，你不用再说了 ，我很累
Uncle ping, don't say anymore, I'm tired.
叫人准备一辆车送我回家吧
Please get me a car and send me home.
晚安
Good night.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
晚安
Good night.
炳叔，现在怎么办？
Uncle ping, what shall we do now?
他不答应，之后再说吧
Let's talk about it later since he refused.
炳叔，不如让阿胜做吧
Uncle ping, why not let shing do?
我？不行
Me? No way.
怎会不行？
Why not?
炳叔，这种事怎么能拖呢？
Uncle ping, this cannot be delayed.
臭口全，何时轮到你作主了？
Bad breath chuen, who are you to speak?
-怎么了？  -炳叔说怎么样就怎么样
- What? - We'll do as uncle ping says.
你算了吧
You shut up.
不要吵了…
Don't argue...
-不要吵了…  -算了…
- Don't argue... - Forget it...
来…
Come on...
算了吧
Forget it.
杨港、砂煲、棺材绳
Yeung Kong, claypot, coffin rope.
完全不用害怕
Fear not.
如果资料正确的话
If the information is correct,
我最怕的是李万豪
I fear Lee man ho the most.
他很有组织能力 ，又有学识
He's skilled at organizing and is well educated.
如果他控制了黑社会
If he controls the triad society,
令黑社会企业化
and make it an enterprise...
到时我们告不了他，反而被他咬一口
We can't deal with him by then, instead we may be ruined by him.
那你们就麻烦了
Then you'll be in great trouble.
（机密）
Confidential
其实我爸做这一行也预计了
Dad should've seen this coming.
我在美国的时候， 每天都怕他出事
I fear something might happen to him when I was in the us.
总之我答应你，做完头七就和你回美国
But I promise you, we'll go back to the states after the funeral.
其实香港也不错，不必那么快离开
Hong Kong is actually good, we don't need to leave so soon.
香港好？
Hong Kong is good?
那你又去美国读书 ，还入籍？
Then why did you study and even naturalize in the us?
我没说过美国不好，如果不好
I never said the us is bad. If it's bad,
我就不会娶到这么好的老婆了
I wouldn't have married a good wife like you.
你真会说话
That's so sweet of you.
走吧
Let's go.
老公，我想多留几天再回美国
Dear, I wish to stay a few more days.
你说好不好？
What do you think?
好，最重要是你喜欢
Sure, as long as you like.
怎么了？没钱开房吗？
Why? You have no money for a room?
理他做甚么？一个小子而已
Ignore him. He's just a boy.
真傻，真无聊
So silly and boring.
陪他们两夫妻看夜景
In order to accompany them to see night view,
害得我不能去跳舞
I can't go to dance tonight.
炳叔吩咐的 ，我们照做吧
We just do as uncle ping said.
话说回来，港哥
By the way, brother Kong,
你跟了炳叔二十年
you've been working for uncle ping for 20 years.
为甚么还当你是小喽啰？
Why is he still treating you like a boy?
你滚蛋吧，炳叔是我大哥
Shut up, uncle ping is my brother.
他养大我，带我出身
He brought me up and gave me a chance.
我没说错呀
But I was right.
你以后别在我面前说这些话
Don't you ever say such things to me.
我不是开玩笑
I mean it.
知道了
Got it.
笨蛋，小心看紧点吧
Silly, watch closer.
李万豪先生
Mr Lee man ho.
我是反黑组的陈天乐
I'm chan tin lok, from anti-triad section.
陈先生，不知道有甚么可以帮你？
Mr chan, how can I be of any help?
我怕你们有危险，想保护你们而已
I came to protect you as I fear you might be in danger.
我又不是黑社会，不用你们保护
I'm not a triad member, no protection is needed.
你要小心点，有人要埋伏你
You must be careful, someone wants to attack you.
你怎么会知道？
How do you know?
我是反黑组，怎么会不知道？
Of course I know. I'm from anti-triad section.
陈先生，你这样说是不是想误导我？
Mr chan, are you trying to mislead me?
保护市民是我们警察的责任
It's our duty to protect the people.
陈警官 ，有甚么事？
Officer chan, what's the matter?
豪哥，你先走吧
Brother ho, you leave first.
陈先生，我先走了
Mr chan, I'll make a move.
杨港，我们收到了消息…
Yeung Kong, we've got news...
我也收到了消息
Me too.
棺材绳嘛，有我在就可以了
Coffin rope right? I can handle it.
用不着你们警察
No need for police.
没有你的事，走吧
There's nothing concerning you, you may leave now.
上车吧
Get in the car.
李万豪
Lee man ho.
你们做甚么？你们不要乱来
What do you want? Don't act rashly.
珍妮…
Jenny...
-珍妮，锁好门  -是
- Jenny, lock the door. - Yes.
救命啊
Help!
阿港
Kong.
先喝杯水吧
Have some water.
谢谢
Thanks.
你叫我怎么说？
What do you want me to say?
你也知道我不会说话
You know I'm not eloquent.
他比较喜欢你嘛，去吧
He likes you better, go.
阿豪
Ho.
你也知道，现在洪兴很乱
As you know, hung hing is now in a chaos.
又没有人可以作主
No one can make decisions.
我看你还是出来帮帮忙吧，好吗？
Can you come and help?
炳叔，我就是不想管
Uncle ping, I prefer not.
如果我要管，我早就跟着我爸出来混了
If I had wanted, I would have followed my father long ago.
你先拿着
Take this.
阿豪
Ho.
你知道吗？刚才人家来摸你的底细
Do you know someone came and checked on you just now?
看到我们不反击
Seeing that we didn't respond,
就会联同其他单位一起来抢我们的地盘
they'll soon join other societies to seize our areas.
面对这样的环境，你也不留下来帮忙？
Facing such critical situation, you still refuse to help?
不要
No!
你们不要再逼我加入黑社会好不好？
Don't force me to be a triad member please.
拿电话来
Get me the phone.
强哥
Brother keung.
帮我找一二三、六七八
Page 123, 678.
叫他召集全部兄弟盯紧工厂
Ask him to gather all our men to keep an eye on the factory.
是厂 ，不是糖
It's factory, not battery.
-盯紧地盘  -就这样吧
- Watch closely. - That's all.
好了…就这样…
Okay... that's all...
你们别再打电话了
Stop calling.
告诉我们有多少个单位想搞我们吧
Tell me how many of them are eyeing us.
六、七、八个左右吧
About six, seven or eight.
其实每一家都想动我们
In fact, every one of them wants us down.
不过最近动静最大的是棺材绳那边
But people of coffin rope are the most ambitious.
他刚从欧洲抢到了几个地盘
He's just got some territories in Europe.
赚了一些钱， 回到香港
Made some money and came back to Hong Kong.
就找了一群越南人帮他
He had some vietnamese to help him.
那你们试试把自己的地盘  租给其他社团吧
Try renting your territories to other societies.
叫他们每个月交租给你们而已
Ask them to pay you rental every month.
做得好的话，以后大家合作下去
If it turns out well, you will cooperate.
有好处的事他们肯定会做
They will do it for their benefits.
如果是你，你也会做吧？
You'll too, won't you?
甚么？租地盘给别人？
What? Let out our territories to others?
那些地盘是我们拿命拼回来的
We fought very hard to get those territories.
他们到时耍花样的话，那怎么办？
What if they seize them?
-香港有个地方叫警局  -还说…
- There's a place called police station. - Shut up...
他们耍花样就报警
Report to the police if they dare.
我们是黑社会，报警？
How can we report to the police as we're the triads?
以后还怎么出来混？
How are we going to face people?
你是黑社会，我可不是
You are but I'm not.
陈天乐沙展
Superintendent chan tin lok.
陈警官 ，我是李万豪
Officer chan, this is Lee man ho.
没事，我想告诉你洪兴社有…
I want to tell you that hung hing has...
你们有多少个地盘？
How many territories do you have?
八个
Eight.
他们有八个地盘
They have eight territories.
这几天会有人搞他们
Someone will get them into trouble these few days.
谢谢你的线报
Thanks for your information.
我们警方会帮你多加留意
We'll watch closely for you.
那就最好了 ，谢谢
That's great, thanks.
我想见见你
I want to meet you.
-好啊，改天喝茶  -好
- Sure, let's find a day. - Okay.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
港哥，有个坏消息要告诉你
Brother Kong, I have bad news for you.
甚么坏消息？
What's that?
炳叔说你这次肯定会升为 「大底」
Uncle ping said you'll be promoted this time.
真的吗？
Really?
水…
Water...
这是滚水
This is hot water.
你想我绝后吗？
You want me to have no offspring?
快扶我起来
Help me up.
你就好了
You're lucky.
我的手啊
My hand.
叔父们开会说你护主有功
The uncles said you did well to protect the master.
礼成
The ceremony is done.
-阿港，恭喜你  -谢谢
- Kong, congratulations. - Thanks.
是我谢谢你才对
I should thank you.
如果在尖东那晚不是你
If it wasn't for you that night at tst east,
我想我已经死了
I would have been killed.
这些都是小事情，我们习惯了
That's nothing. We're used to it.
（洪兴社）
Hung hing gang
重新写
write it again.
喂？
Hello?
全哥吗？
Brother chuen?
找阿胜？
Looking for shing?
他出去了 ，对…
He's gone out, yes...
怎样凡是找我的都说我出去了
What now? Why did you tell everyone I'm out?
不要去
Don't go.
喂？
Hello?
我是， 阿嫂以为我出去了
Shing's speaking, my wife thought I was out.
这样吗？好，我马上出来
Is it? Okay, I'll be right there.
麻烦帮我传呼一七四
Please page 174.
二七四 ，三七四 ，全三七，孖二
Also 274, 374, 537 and 22.
你说阿胜叫他们准备好货物
Tell them shing asks them to get the stuff ready.
去上海街富豪舞厅里等他
Then wait for him at regal ballroom on Shanghai street.
是，谢谢
Yes, thanks.
-小心一点  -知道了
- Be careful. - Sure.
-再见，爸爸  -再见
- Bye, dad. - Bye.
菩萨保佑，保佑阿胜出入平安
God, please Grant shing safety.
万事顺顺利利，逢凶化吉
That he can overcome all difficulties.
棺材绳，油尖旺三区加起来
Coffin rope, adding up the three areas in yau tsim mong,
我们总共有四个夜总会
we have four nightclubs in total,
三间麻雀馆， 两间牌九馆
three mahjong shops and two domino shops.
一个月有150万
We get one and a half million a month.
先给我们三个月上期
Give us three months of down payment.
至于看场就由我们自己做
We'll oversee the security and management.
甚么？看场你也自己做？
What? You will oversee?
那我的兄弟吃甚么？吃西北风吗？
What about my men? They do nothing?
这样的条件，我租给你做吧
What about I rent it to you with such conditions?
棺材绳，条件就是这样
Coffin rope, this is the condition.
总之包你有好处
I assure you'll benefit from it.
我可以给帐簿你看
I can show you the ledgers.
不用了 ，帐簿是你做的
No need, you created the ledgers.
天文数字，你喜欢怎么写都可以
You can make it any way you like.
这样吧， 先做一个星期
What about carrying this out for a week?
你认为可以考虑的话才跟我租吧
We shall continue if you think it's doable.
我当然想租了 ，胜哥
Of course I want to rent, brother shing.
但是哪有这么便宜的事？
But is there really free meal in the world?
棺材绳，我们老大的事你们也知道
Coffin rope, you know about my boss.
现在我们被警方看得很紧
We're now being closely watched by the police.
否则我也不用租给你
If not, we won't rent either.
很多单位都想要我们的生意
Many people want our business.
你不租就算了 ，走
Forget it then, let's go.
胜哥，不必动气
Brother shing, don't get angry.
坐下来慢慢商量吧
Sit down and we shall talk it over.
这样吧
Okay.
先租一个星期看看情况
We'll rent for a week and see how it goes.
拿帐簿来吧
Bring me the ledger.
麻烦让一让
Excuse me.
-不说了  -黐根
- Let's not talk about it. - Lunatic.
傻强，有甚么事跑来我们这里？
Mad keung, why are you here?
没甚么 ，想找你们老大谈谈而已
Nothing, I'd like to talk to your boss.
我们和你们有甚么好谈的
What is there to discuss?
我们想租地盘给你们 ，谈不谈？
What if we want to rent you our territories?
租地盘？
Rent your territories?
傻强，老实说吧，有甚么大阴谋？
Mad keung, what plan do you have in mind?
我看你也不能话事
I don't think you can decide.
-叫你老大出来吧  -等等吧
- Ask your boss out. - Just a moment.
老大，傻强找你
Boss, mad keung wants to see you.
傻强，你们洪兴有甚么好处给我们？
Mad keung, what does hung hing have for us?
来，过来谈谈吧
Come, let's talk about it.
去出面看
Have a look.
-标哥，有甚么事就找我吧  -好的
- Brother biu, call me if there's anything. - Okay.
就这样吧
That's it.
老大，真的这么便宜我们？
Boss, is there such a good bargain?
黑社会说话， 先信一半吧
Don't believe everything a triad member says.
-对吧？  对
- Right? - Yes.
别跑
Stop running.
全部带走
Take them.
别动…
Don't move...
站住，别跑
Stop, don't run.
好呀…
Okay...
甚么事…
What's going on...
怎么回事？
What's going on?
去死吧…
Go to hell...
站好了
Stand still.
-你是哪里的？  -怎么了？
- Where are you from? - Why?
你知不知道我是这里的陀地？
Don't you know I'm the boss here?
有甚么好看？走吧
Nothing to see, go away.
不看就不看
What's so cocky about?
还不走？走啊
Still here? Go away.
小子  以后有甚么就跟我说，知道了吗？
Kid, let me know if there's anything, okay?
还不叫港哥？
Call him brother Kong.
叫啊
Say.
港哥
Brother Kong.
以后大家就是兄弟了
We are brothers now.
来吧
Come on.
上次做得很好，继续在学校找手下
You did a good job last time, continue to find me some kids.
要机灵的
I need smart ones.
港哥
Brother Kong.
-拿去吧  -谢谢港哥
- Take it. - Thanks, brother Kong.
阿嫂，搞得定吗？
Sister, are things manageable?
可以，你先坐下来喝杯茶吧，炳叔
Yes. Uncle ping, why don't you sit down and have some tea?
蒸鱼能难倒很多人
Steaming fish can be troublesome.
这倒是
You're right.
-阿强  -甚么？
Keung. “What?
怎么不见阿港来？
Why didn't Kong come?
我找了他，但是整天都没有回复我
I've called him all day but got no reply from him.
打他的手提电话
I called his mobile phone.
又老是外国女人在说话，麻烦
But a foreign lady answered.
他这阵子可威风了
He's getting more successful.
收了很多手下
Having many men working for him,
还到处收保护费
and collecting money everywhere.
来…好东西…
Come... here is something good...
-好东西啊  -炳叔，你老人家就不要这么辛苦了
- It's good. - Uncle ping, you shouldn't do this.
这些事让女人来做就好了
Let the women do this.
这你就错了 ，她们没有这么好的手艺
You're wrong. They can't cook as well as I do.
知道了吗？
Got it?
那倒是
You're right.
别啰嗦了 ，吃饭了
Talk no more, let's eat.
大嫂
Sister.
你们慢慢吃吧，还有很多菜
Enjoy the food. There're many more dishes.
-你不吃就算了  -乖，吃饭吧， 尝一尝
- Fine, if you don't want to. - Have some rice, try this.
常常吃汉堡包怎么行呢？
You can't always eat burgers.
-妈妈拿给你吃  -好
- Let me take for you. - Okay.
这个很好吃的 ，试一下吧
This is delicious, try some.
喂？我是…是阿水啊
Hello? Speaking... oh, it's shui.
甚么事？
What is it?
就这样吧，我在吃饭
Alright. I'm eating now.
这只鸡很好吃的 ， 多吃点吧
This chicken tastes good, have some more.
-好不好吃？  -好吃
- Is it tasty? - Yes.
阿强，现在外面乱成一团
Keung, it's chaos out there.
到处都是人马
People from all sides are showing up.
阿豪，这招有效
Ho, your method works.
你一定要留下来帮我们
You must stay and help.
你省口气， 暖暖肚子
Save that and eat more.
明天买份报纸看看抓了多少人更好
Get a newspaper tomorrow and see how many are arrested.
对吧？老婆，鱼腩好吃吗？
Right? Dear, is the fish good?
好吃
Yes.
尽快把合同交给他们签了吧
Get the contract ready as soon as possible.
有你们关照 ，甚么时候都可以
I can sign anytime.
不
No.
生意归生意
Business is business.
千万不要说关照
We must be serious.
大家做生意，还是要公正点
We should be fair in doing business.
傻强，你过来，我老大找你
Mad keung, come over, my boss wants to see you.
甚么事？
What is it?
黐根，甚么事？
Lunatic, what is it?
傻强，不必这么大声
Mad keung, don't be so loud.
我老大找你，有事要跟你说
My boss has something to talk to you.
你瞎了吗？没看见我在谈事情吗？
Are you blind? Can't you see I'm busy?
-有事之后再说  -傻强
- Talk later if you must. - Mad keung.
小弟 ，为甚么你这边刚租地盘给我
Why is it just after you'd rented me the place,
那边就马上有仇家来了
that people came giving me trouble?
接着警察又杀到
Then police came...
封铺又捉人，你怎么交待？
And arrested my men. What do you say?
标哥，租地盘的事你情我愿
Brother biu, we agreed on the business.
有事你就来找我，那我还过得下去？
Now you come to me when things go wrong, won't I be busy?
现在你真的是过不去
Now you're really in trouble.
给西瓜皮我踩？
How dare you fool me?
-这怎么算？  -开玩笑吗 ，标哥？
- How can you compensate? - Are you kidding, brother biu?
出来混，谁没有仇家？
Who has no rivals as a triad member?
那么容易打理我还要租给你吗？
Why would I let it to you if it was easy?
这是你的事， 总之你陷害我就不行
That's your business, but you mustn't trick me.
现在我有十几个手下被捉了
Now, I have same ...
还有几个进了医院
Some were even admitted.
律师费、医药费等等，谁来付？
Who's going to pay for the legal and medical fees?
我替你说了吧
I've an idea.
这半年的租费由你出
You'll pay the rent for the next six months.
甚么 ，你当我洪兴是甚么？
What? What do you think hung hing is?
你冤枉我？
You frame me?
-傻强  -怎么样？
- Mad keung. - What?
跟我老大说话客气点
Be polite to my boss.
可恶
Darn it.
不要动…
Don't move...
阿强
Keung.
不要动手
Stop it.
你们做甚么？
What are you doing?
对标叔的人这么没规矩的吗？
How can you be so rude to uncle biu's men?
标叔，有事慢慢商量
Uncle biu, we can discuss.
兄弟 ，你以甚么身分跟我老大说话？
Brother, who are you to talk to my boss?
坐馆
I'm the head.
标哥，大家都是自己人
Uncle biu, we're of the same kind.
坐下来慢慢谈吧
Let's sit down and discuss.
阿豪现在做坐馆了吗？
Is ho officially the head now?
按理说我应该知道的
Why didn't I know?
这位是我们的新龙头
This is our new head.
你不知道是你自己住得偏僻
It's your problem if you didn't know about it.
你以为是山口组和黑手党吗？
You think this is yamakuchi or Italian triad?
做老大也要登报纸上电视
Do we have to advertise?
要不要开记者招待会？现在我说是就是
Or maybe a press conference? What I say counts.
好了…不要吵了
Okay... stop that.
这是事实
But this is truth.
好，我就当你是，那你怎么向我交待？
Okay, I believe you are, but how do you explain?
标哥， 出来混的谁没有仇家
Brother biu, everyone has rivals.
地盘我们已经租给了你
We've rented you the place.
有事当然是你们单位自己处理
You should hold the responsibility if things go wrong.
怎能说是我们单位陷害你？
How can you say we trick you?
兄弟 ，这就是说我…
Brother, you mean I...
好，我们坐下来谈
Okay, let's sit down and talk.
你们出去
You go out.
阿强，我不放心
Keung, I'm worried.
没事的 ，他会处理，我们出去吧
Don't worry, he'll fix it, let's go out.
标叔
Uncle bi...
你也知道我是被迫的
You know I was forced to.
这么多的兄弟也要混口饭吃
My men need a living.
有甚么事就好好说清楚
We must try and solve any problem.
对，说得对
Yes, you're right.
但是赚钱要公道
But we must make money the right way.
尤其是我们做老大的 ，不能太不择手段
Especially leaders like us, we should be reasonable.
标叔，过去的事抹掉就算了
Uncle biu, let bygones be bygones.
你们那边的费用由我负责
I'll take care of all your charges.
不知道你老人家意下如何？
What do you think?
好，就一句话说好
Great, it's a deal.
谢谢
Thank you.
其实现在做老大也很烦
It's not easy to be leaders.
说的是，现在做喽啰比做老大好
Right, it's easier to be the followers.
所以说最重要的是和气生财
So we must be on good terms.
有钱大家一起赚， 是吧？
We can make money together, right?
死去的坤老大没有生错你
It's good that your dad has a son like you.
也要多谢标叔给我面子
Thanks to you too, uncle bi...
以后要多多关照
Please look out for me.
来，喝茶
Let's have some tea.
我们先上车
We'll make a move.
-一会见，你们两个去那边  -先走了
- See you later, you two go over there. - I'll leave first.
-我坐他们的车  -再见
- I'll follow their car. - Bye.
走吧
Let's go.
都不知道阿标是怎么回事，疯了
I wonder what's wrong with bi...
阿胜，小心啊
Shing, be careful.
开车撞他
Knock him down.
追他…
Run after him...
快点…
Quick...
阿强，看着阿豪，快去
Keung, protect ho, quick.
走啊，快走，开车
Run, quick, start the car.
怎么回事啊？
What's going on?
刚才不是跟标叔说好了吗？
Didn't we make it clear to uncle biu?
是呀，标叔不会这么没有道义的
Yeah, uncle biu won't be so cunning.
一定是棺材绳他们
It must be coffin rope.
炳叔，怎么办？
What shall we do, uncle ping?
打他
Beat him.
快点…
Quick...
停车
Stop the car.
小心点，要镇定
Be careful. Take it easy.
阿豪，走
Ho, let's go.
快点…
Quick...
看着豪哥
Protect brother ho.
胜哥，你快点送他去医院吧
Brother shing, take him to the hospital.
你只是给他敷中药是不行的
You can't just treat him with herbal medicine.
行，我常常都是这样治我的手下
It works, I always treat my men with this.
只是撞伤了而已 ，没事的
Just a minor injury, it's okay.
没事？你看他伤成这样，还说没事？
It's okay? He's seriously wounded and you think it's okay?
阿胜
Shing.
阿豪，不要乱来
Ho, don't do that.
这件事张扬出去  我们整个单位都有麻烦
We'll be in trouble if this spreads.
你再不送他去医院，他就定死了
He'll die if you don't send him to the hospital.
阿豪，你也不是不知道，我们出来混的
Ho, you know what we do.
有甚么伤也只能自己处理
We can only heal ourselves if we get injured.
进医院？难道说他自己摔伤了？
Take him to the hospital? Can we say he hurt himself?
那你告诉我他伤势如何吧
Tell me how serious he is now.
医好了 ，也会变残废
He's sure to be disabled.
他的筋都断了
All his limbs are broken.
炳叔
Uncle ping.
找到阿港了吗？
Have you found Kong?
我叫了所有兄弟到处找他
I've sent my men to locate him.
-找到了就告诉我  -是
- Tell me if you find him. - Sure.
爸爸，妈妈 ，我放学了
Daddy, mommy, I'm back from school.
放学了？乖， 先放下书包吧
Good, put down your school bag first.
现在他弄成这个样子
Now that he's seriously injured,
我都不知道如何跟他家人交待
how am I going to tell his family?
公家拿点钱出来给他当家用吧
Take some money from our account as compensation.
你也说了 ，就算他治好也会残废
If he's surely disabled,
给多少钱他也没用
what's the use of money?
好吧，我们马上去把棺材绳砍了给你看
Alright, we'll hunt coffin rope down.
我真不明白你们这些人
I just can't understand.
只懂得打打杀杀 ，这能解决事情吗？
Do fighting and killing solve problems?
阿豪，你别忘了
Ho, don't forget.
没有我们替你老爸打天下
If we hadn't fought for your dad,
你会有今天吗？还不是会和我们一样
where would you have been now? You would've been just like us.
这件事因你而起
You caused all this.
你还怪我们的兄弟
How can you blame us?
对呀，你的命生得好
Right, you're lucky.
小时候你跟人打架
When you were small and fought with others,
还不是我们帮你处理
we took care of it for you.
还在这里啰啰嗦嗦
And now you're murmuring.
现在要说小时候的事是吗？
Talking about the past, huh?
要不是小时候那件事我向老爸求情
If I hadn't begged my father for you,
你们还会有今天吗？
what would you have become today?
每次都让我为难
Always put me in a dilemma.
幸好刚才标叔给我们面子
Luckily uncle biu did us a favor.
否则我们全都被杀了
Otherwise, we would've all been killed.
-你说甚么？  -怎么了？
What did you say? “What?
你说我们让你为难？
You said we put you in dilemma?
是你自己要去的 ，还怪我们
You insisted to do so and now you're blaming us?
-你不是太子的话，我一拳打死你  -你想怎么样？
- 1'd kill you if you weren't our boss' son. - What do you want?
-不要喊打喊杀的  -好了…
- Don't behave like that. - Okay...
你们别吵了行吗？
Stop arguing, please?
老公
Dear.
爸爸
Daddy.
看甚么 ，你儿子叫你，还不过去
Your son is calling you. Why don't you go over?
蠢材
Stupid.
我知道
I know.
-爸爸  -乖
- Daddy. - Good boy.
甚么事？
What's going on?
先出去 ，来吧
Let's go out.
阿豪， 发生了甚么事？
Ho, what happened?
你怎么全身都是血？
Why do you have blood all over?
他们在做甚么？
Why are they here?
我都不知道怎么跟你说
I don't know how to tell you.
你不用跟我说，我们明天一起走
No need, we shall leave tomorrow.
这里实在太危险了
It's too dangerous here.
那个兄弟是为了我才弄成这样
That guy got injured because of me.
如果我走了 ，我还是人吗？
How can I leave now?
他们这些人早晚都是这样的下场
They are doomed to end up like this.
你说甚么？他们也是人
What? They are also humans.
如果不是他，我已经死了
If it hadn't been for him, I would've been killed.
如果你要走，你跟阿祖一起回去吧
If you must leave, take Joe with you.
不要哭了 ， 阿祖
Don't cry, Joe.
过去妈妈那里，替爸爸说对不起
Go to mommy and apologize for me.
去吧
Go.
妈妈 ，爸爸跟你说对不起
Mommy, daddy says sorry to you.
我早跟你说过这件事没有结果的
I've told you this cannot be solved.
带我去见阿港吧
Take me to Kong.
-雄仔  -大哥
- Hong. - Boss.
替我看着牙屎
Keep an eye on dirt for me.
-有甚么事就打电话去麻雀馆找我  -是
- Call me at mahjong shop if there's anything. - Yes.
看好了 ， 记着要扎拿武器的手
Look, put the tape on the arm with weapon.
这样扎着就不怕砍错人
Then you won't kill the wrong person.
有没有搞错，我们等了你一个小时
We've been waiting for you for an hour.
-塞车  -快点
- There was a traffic jam. - Quick.
跪下吧，跪下
Kneel down...
炳叔，豪哥
Uncle ping, brother ho.
-阿港呢？  -在里面
- Where's Kong? - He's inside.
要兄弟还是要黄金？
You want brothers or gold?
快说
Say.
阿港
Kong.
-你来做甚么？  -我现在问你，你在这里做甚么？
- Why are you here? - I'm asking you why you're here.
找人做替死鬼
Finding a man to be scapegoat.
那件事不用你管，我会处理
It's okay, I'll settle it.
你来处理？怎么处理？
You? How?
阿港，你听阿豪说吧
Kong, listen to ho.
大哥，这件事你也知道没有商量的余地
Boss, you know there's no way to solve it.
现在一定要杀掉棺材绳
We must kill coffin rope.
豪哥，这件事让我来解决
Brother ho, leave it to me.
阿港，那孩子连书包都还放下
Kong, that boy is still studying.
你不要连累人家
Don't ruin him.
豪哥，其实坤叔以前也是这样教我们
Brother ho, uncle kwan used to teach us like that.
要找一些未成年的人来顶罪
To find kids who are underage to be scapegoats.
我也是这样从小到大砍砍杀杀
I used to be like this too.
-炳叔，我想去摩罗街走走  -好
- Uncle ping, I'm taking a walk at lascar row. - Okay.
星仔， 陪豪哥去走走
Sing, keep brother ho company.
不用了 ，我想找他去 ，谢谢
It's okay, I want him to go with me, thanks.
不用
No worries.
来吧
Come on.
你叫甚么名字？
What's your name?
德仔
Tak.
-你知道你在这里做甚么吗？  -打架
- Do you know what you're doing here? - Fighting.
-你害怕吗？  -怕
- Are you afraid? - Yes.
丧滔，他出来了
Crazy to, he's out.
捉住他…
Get him...
上车
Get in the car.
开车
Start the car.
警察，走吧…
Police, run...
快走…
Move...
不要走
Don't run.
站住
Stop.
不要动，站住…
Don't move, stand still...
别跑…
Don't run...
趴下
Get down.
-是我…是我做的  -不要动
- It's me... I did it. - Don't move.
警察不会指条黑路给你走的
I won't mislead you.
口说无凭，你不用哄我了
You needn't cheat me.
最多不过是坐几年牢
I might as well go to jail.
就像彩排过一样，全部对答如流
He answered as if everything was rehearsed.
看下去就知道了
Watch and you'll know.
有证有据？你开玩笑吗 ，警官？
There's evidence? Are you joking, sir?
小子， 是谁指使你做的？
Who instructed you to do this?
你收了多少安家费？
How much have you taken?
-陈警官  -李先生
- Officer chan. - Mr Lee.
只会累你一辈子
It'll ruin you forever.
李先生，麻烦你，不好意思
Mr Lee, sorry to bother you.
别客气，我们市民应该做的
No worries, it's my responsibility as a citizen.
坐吧
Have a seat.
是吗？说来听听
Is it? Tell us.
港督、英女王
The hk governor, her majesty,
廉政公署、投诉组，怎么样？
icac, the complaints unit, how's that?
耍我，你欠揍吗？
Fooling me? You want me to beat you?
-小子，不要说我不照顾你  -这个孩子，你认识吗？
- Kid, don't say I don't care for you. - Do you know this kid?
不认识
No, I don't.
他跟我有关吗？
Is there anything to do with me?
谁是你的老大？
Who is your boss?
-说啊  -那你知不知道两个小时之前
- Tell me. - Did you know that two hours ago,
在九龙塘发生了一桩砍人事件？
there was an assault in kowloon tong?
-不知道  -真的不知道？
- I don't know. - For real?
有线报说今次是你策划的
We've got information saying that you planned it.
警官 ，如果你再跟我这样说话
Sir, if you talk to me like this,
我就找个律师跟你说
I'll call for my lawyer.
好了 ，李先生
Okay, mr Lee.
那你现在是不是洪兴坐馆？
Are you now the head of hung hing?
不是
No.
不是就最好了
It's good that you're not.
是的话，我就拘捕你了
I'd arrest you if you were.
两位警官 ，如果没有甚么事，我先走了
Sir, I'll leave if there's nothing else.
-有甚么事就打电话给我吧  -好
- Give me a call if you need me. - Sure.
李先生
Mr Lee.
你认不认识他？
Do you know him?
认识
Yes.
-李嘉诚嘛  -敢跟警官开玩笑？
- Lee ka shing. - You fool with sir?
-不要动手动脚  -走
- Don't do that. - Let's go.
李先生，可以给我一根烟抽吗？
Mr Lee, mind giving me a cigarette?
-谢了  -走吧
- Thanks. - Go.
傻强，有种就杀了我
Mad keung, kill me if you dare.
来吧，动手吧
Come on, kill me.
等甚么 ，来吧
What are you waiting for? Come on.
去死吧，混蛋
Go to hell, scum.
这算甚么英雄？
This is not heroic.
来， 杀了我吧，来吧
Come on, kill me.
不要乱来
Don't act rashly.
过来吧，杀了我吧
Come on, kill me.
-不要乱来，你已经杀了一个了  -别拦着我
- Stop, you've killed one. - Don't stop me.
阿豪很快就回来了
Ho is coming back soon.
-我杀了他  -不要
- I want to kill him. - No.
胜哥
Brother shing.
-阿港，你做甚么？  -阿港
- Kong, what are you doing? - Kong.
阿港
Kong.
坐下
Sit down.
豪哥，这个是你的 ，来吧
Ho, this is yours, come on.
替牙屎报仇吧
Take revenge for dirt.
小子，要杀就杀干脆点
Kid, just kill.
不要思前想后
Don't hesitate.
杀是吧
Kill you, huh?
你耍我是吧，去死吧
You fooling me? Go to hell.
豪哥，要不要我帮忙？
Brother ho, do you need my help?
多事，阿豪自己会决定
Brother Ho can be...
等等
Wait.
阿豪，这是社团的事， 让我来解决
Ho, this is our society's affair, leave it to me.
胜哥
Brother shing.
剃了他的眉毛，让他以后想清楚
Shave off his eyebrows and let him think over.
想甚么想，要杀就杀
What to think about? Just kill me.
剃眉毛算甚么英雄？
You're not a hero if you shave my eyebrows.
-你闭嘴  -还说？
- Shut up. - Dare you say anymore?
豪哥，这样不行
Brother ho, we can't do that.
放虎归山 ，肯定会有问题
It'll be problematic if you let him go.
阿豪，阿港说得对
Ho, Kong is right.
这样不行
This won't work.
你们还不动手
What are you still waiting for?
不是阿豪的话就杀了你
I would've killed you if it hadn't been ho.
便宜了你，剃掉你的眉毛
You're lucky. Shaving your eyebrows...
跟你的光头更配了
Matches your baldness.
走吧
Go.
现在豪哥放你一马 ，给你一点教训
Now brother ho is letting you go as a lesson.
还不多谢豪哥？
Thank brother ho.
我们走
Let's go.
以后做人就醒目点
Be smarter.
你有本事
Watch out.
上来吧…
Come on...
老大，今天洪兴取得了头炮
Boss, hung hing got the top today.
是啊…
Yeah...
好…
Good...
炳叔，以后全靠你了
Uncle ping, we rely on you from now on.
胜哥，坐馆的位子你不要推了
Brother shing, don't reject to be the head.
-阿豪，我…  -胜哥，我一定要走的
- Ho, I... - Brother shing, I'll leave one day.
这里没事，让我跟他说
It's okay, let me talk to him.
我们先去酒楼打点一下
We'll get ready at the restaurant.
阿港，你发甚么脾气？
Kong, why are you so angry?
你喜欢的话  我就叫胜哥把坐馆的位子给你
I'll ask brother shing to let you be the head if you like.
不是喜不喜欢
It's not about if I like it.
是应不应该
It's that well did.
只会让老家伙作主
If the seniors are always in power,
洪兴早晚就倒了
hung hing will soon collapse.
你也不想你爸爸的生意倒闭吧
You don't want to ruin your dad's business, do you?
你现在还年轻，找份正当职业吧
You're still young, find a proper job.
豪哥，我很还小的时候就跟了你爸爸
Brother ho, I've followed your dad since young.
现在字也不认得多少个，能做甚么？
I can't even read, what can I do?
做便利店，还是快餐店？
Work at 7-11 or McDonald's?
做黑社会哪里有回头路？
There's no turning back for triad members.
你以为是你吗？可以去外国读书
I'm not you, who could study abroad.
豪哥，这里不适合你的 ， 回美国吧
Brother ho, this is not your place, you'd better go back to the states.
请
This way.
-动作快点，真笨  -五叔， 随便坐吧，招呼不周
- Move faster, you fool. - Uncle wu, make yourself at home.
这些东西现在才拿出来，怎么搞的
How can you take these out so late?
快点拿过去
Quick
现在我有一班兄弟帮忙做装修
I've friends who do renovation.
-有空就关照一下吧  -好啊
- Help them if you can. - Sure.
这位是鸿哥
This is brother hung.
-鸿哥  -港哥
- Brother hung. - Brother Kong.
-怎么这么晚才到  -招呼不周 ，请里面坐
- Why are you so late? - Please go inside.
-鸿哥  -怎么样？
- Brother hung. - Yes?
-最近码头那边我也不错  -是
- I've business at the pier. - I see.
有时间出来研究一下
Let's talk about it sometime.
-那真的要谈谈了  -好
- Sure. - Great.
来，干杯…
Come on, cheers...
-干杯…  -敬你的
- Cheers... - Cheers to you.
请这边走
This way please.
-你好，李先生…  -你好， 马里奥先生
- Hello, mr Lee... - Hello, mr Mario.
你好，今天才到吗？
Hello, just arrived today?
替我告诉他， 明晚我请他吃饭
Tell him I'll treat him to dinner tomorrow.
我老大想请你吃饭
My boss would like to invite you for dinner.
-谢谢…  -他说谢谢
- Thank you... - He says thank you.
阿港，你坐在这里做甚么？
Kong, what are you doing here?
帮忙招呼客人吧，去吧…
Help to serve the guests, come on...
你…
You...
阿豪、炳叔，怎么这么晚？
Ho, uncle ping, why are you so late?
有点事情要做
We had something urgent.
怎么这么晚才到，我还以为你来不了
You're late. I thought you weren't coming.
不要乱说
Don't talk nonsense.
年青人
Young man.
-标叔  -这么晚
- Uncle biu. - So late.
来了很久吗？坐…
You've been here long? Sit...
标叔，你这只古董表真漂亮
Uncle biu, this antique watch is nice.
1920年的劳力士
It's rolex of 1920.
-是吗？  -瓷面玫瑰金的
- Is it? - It's porcelain and Rose gold.
让小弟开开眼界吧
May I have a look?
怎么样？
What do you think?
真的很少有的
It's rare.
在这里做甚么？真是蠢材
What are you doing here? You fool.
-试音…  -记着
- Testing... - Remember.
做老大最重要的是要一视同仁
A leader must be fair.
千万不要偏重一边
You mustn't be biased.
各位兄弟、来宾
My fellow men and guests.
今晚很感谢大家光临，驾临
We thank you for coming tonight.
现在我们的办事人有点事跟大家说
Now our host has something to tell you.
说完就开始投标
Then we'll start the auction.
有请李万豪先生
Let's welcome mr Lee man ho.
叫你呢
It's you.
请
Please.
各位
Dear all.
小弟很高兴能够在这里跟大家说几句话
I'm honored to be here to talk to you all.
今晚我主要是想说说
I just want to talk about...
洪兴社以后的业务发展问题
The future development of hung hing.
因为本人会短期内离开香港， 回去美国
As I'll be leaving for the us soon,
以后社团所有的业务就交给炳叔处理
uncle ping will be responsible for all the businesses concerning the society.
至于办事人的职务就由谢胜先生接任
And mr tse shing will be the head.
本人谨代表洪兴社同人
On behalf of hung hing society,
谢谢各位今晚来临参加天后宝诞的盛会
I thank you for coming to the celebration of tin hau's birthday.
大家多喝几杯
Enjoy yourselves.
各位，现在投标开始了
Let the auction begin.
你们可以一边吃，一边投标
You may bid while eating.
首先是发财福鼠一只，底价是五百元
First, it's a fortune mouse at 500 dollars.
五千
Five thousand.
美国马菲亚公司出五千
Mafia company from us offers 5,000 dollars.
五千元，有没有人出价高于五千元？
Anyone offers more than that?
一万
Ten thousand.
林律师出价一万
Solicitor lam offers 10,000 dollars.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
林大状，他们几个是美国黑手党
Solicitor lam, they're triad members from the us.
你投另外一件吧，不好意思
You'd better bid other items, sorry.
有没有？
Anymore?
两万
Twenty thousand.
美国马菲亚公司出价两万
Mafia from us offers 20,000 dollars.
-有没有谁的出价高于两万元？  -这群人很给面子我们
- Anyone more than 20,000 dollars? - They're really giving us face.
-有没有？  -不用怕
- Anyone? - Don't panic.
-有没有？  -谢谢
- Anyone? - Thanks.
一，二，三，成交，谢谢
One, two, three, it's a deal, thanks.
全开，对手宝…
All, both hands...
现在是长虹一条，底价一万
Now it's a piece of red scarf at 10,000 dollars.
底价一万，有没有人出价？
Original price at 10,000 dollars. Any offers?
-大哥， 出价吧  -底价一万
- Boss, bid now. - Original price 10,000 dollars.
两万
Twenty thousand.
广香堂出价两万，有人出多于两万吗？
Kwong heung hall offers 20,000 dollars, anyone more than that?
-叫阿祖吧  -两万
- Call Joe. - Twenty thousand dollars.
-三万  -有没有人出价高于两万？
- Thirty thousand dollars. - Anyone more than 20,000 dollars?
-三万  -出到三万了 ，三万
- Thirty thousand dollars. - It's 30,000 dollars now.
有没有人出价高于三万？三万
Anyone more than 30,000 dollars?
-有没有…三万  -十万
- Anyone... 30,000 dollars. - 100,000 dollars.
-十万，有没有人出价高于十万  -跟我争？
- 100,000 dollars, anyone more than that? - Fight with me?
十五万
One hundred and fifty thousand dollars.
炳叔，我看他志在必得
Uncle ping, he insists on getting it.
-不要玩了  -怎样争…
- Forget it. - What can we do?
二十万
Two hundred thousand dollars.
二十五万
Two hundred and fifty thousand dollars.
混蛋，想跟我玩花样？
Trying to fool me?
这样玩法可不行，会很麻烦
It'll be troublesome if this goes on.
制止一下吧
Stop him.
-不要阻止我，让我教训那小子  -炳叔，你做甚么 ，不要这样
- Don't stop me, I must teach him a lesson. - Uncle ping, what are you trying to do?
阿港，你在做甚么？他们始终是客人
Kong, what are you doing? They are our guests.
碍我好事，分分钟一世倒楣
You'll be doomed if you get in my way.
三十万
Three hundred thousand dollars.
-波哥  -怎么了 ，胜哥？
- Brother Bo. - Yes, brother shing?
不好意思，手下多喝了两杯
I'm sorry, my boy is drunk.
喝多了？
He's drunk?
五十万
Five hundred thousand dollars.
你也看见了
Now you see.
我一心来捧你场 ，想投一条长虹
I came to support you and wanted to buy this.
-他要跟我对着投，这是甚么意思？  -不是这个意思
- He's now getting in my way. - He didn't mean it.
我们走
Let's go.
波哥…不要这样
Brother Bo... please.
真是的
Sigh.
-混蛋，不要拦我  -怎么了…
- Scum. Don't stop me. - Don't...
-让我把他打醒  -不要…
- Let me teach him a lesson. - Don't...
-你走开  -不要这样
- Go away. - Don't be like this.
阿港，你玩够了吗？
Kong, have you played enough?
现在弄成这样，你很开心吗？
Are you happy that you made this mess?
闭嘴吧，你是甚么身分？
Shut up. Who are you?
我为甚么要听你的？你省省吧
Why must I listen to you? Save it.
-你疯够了吗？  -你打我？
- Have you fooled enough? - You beat me?
-阿港，不要这样  -阿胜，别打了 ，阿胜
- Kong, don't be like that. - Shing, stop, shing.
混蛋
Scum.
-阿胜，你怎么了 ，你不要这样  -这里没有女人的事，走开
- Shing, what are you doing? Don't do that. - None of your business, go away.
-胜哥，坐下来吧…  -坐下来
- Brother shing, sit down... - Sit down.
-这是怎么了？  -不要这样
- What's wrong with you? - Don't do that.
-谢胜，这笔账我一定会和你算  -你冷静点
- Tse shing, I'll remember this. - Calm down.
你玩甚么？
Say no more.
-拉他出去  -走呀
- Drag him out. - Go.
-你这么冲动做甚么？  -先坐下来
- Why are you so rash? - Sit down first.
是他不对，这么丢脸的事也做得出
How could he do such a shameful thing?
胜哥，嫂子刚刚走了
Brother shing, your wife's just left.
快出去追她吧
Go and find her.
-是啊，快点追  -去呀
- Yeah, quick. - Go.
来，快点，走吧
Come on, quick, go now.
-臭小子  -来…
- Scum. - Come on...
没事的 ， 是喝多了 ，一时上火而已
It's all right, he's just drunk and lost his temper.
世侄
Nephew.
这件事显然是造反 ，很麻烦的
This is obviously a rebel. It'll bring us trouble.
老婆
Honey.
（我要回美国）
I am going back to U.S.A.
（旺角夜总会）
Mong kok night club
老大，杨港在那边大吵大闹
boss, yeung Kong is mad over there.
在哪里？
Where?
那边
There.
甚么难做…
What's so difficult...
我不懂甚么规矩
I don't care about the regulations.
甚么 ，你是新来的吗？真不识好歹
What? Are you new? You know nothing.
-让我来…  -你醒目点
- Let me... - Be smart.
有事慢慢商量
Take it easy.
阿港，我知道你今晚心情不太好
Kong, I know you're in a bad mood.
做喽啰是难，但是做老大也不容易
Being followers is hard, but being leaders is not easy either.
虽然是这样  但是在那么多手下面前打我
I know, but slapping me in public,
我以后还怎么出来混，你说是吗？
how am I going to face my men?
老弟 ，凭良心说
Frankly speaking,
今晚这件事是你不对在先
you were at fault first.
也不能全怪阿胜
You can't blame shing solely.
你今晚吵吵闹闹
You made a mess tonight.
有没有为阿豪想一想
Have you spared a thought for ho?
我没有难为阿豪，我不服谢胜罢了
I didn't bring ho trouble, I just can't stand tse shing.
如果你不服阿胜，可以找他出来单挑
If you can't stand shing, you can challenge him one-on-one.
在众人面前搞事
If you make a mess in public,
你们的社团只会成为笑柄，对不对？
you'll only be laughed by others, right?
两夫妻，有事就慢慢商量
We can discuss things over.
每次我叫你金盆洗手，你都说再晚一点
Every time I ask you to quit, you'll say later.
你知道吗 ，你每次走出这个门口
Do you know every time you walk out of this door,
我就担心再也见不到你
I fear I can't see you anymore?
刚才如果不是那些人按着你
If they hadn't stopped you,
你还不是又弄得一身伤回来
you would've got injured again.
你第一天认识我吗？
Is this the first day you know me?
你还没嫁给我的时候
Before you married me,
也知道我是出来混的
you'd known about my job.
阿胜，今时不同往日
Shing, the world has changed.
现在的年轻人没有人性
Young people nowadays are crazy.
他们不会跟你说江湖道义
They don't care about righteousness.
我嫁给你的时候，没有想过要大鱼大肉
I didn't ask for a rich life when I married you.
只求一家三口平平安安
I only want a peaceful life.
阿娟 ，我知道你对我好
Kuen, I know you're good to me.
但是人在江湖，有时候真的是身不由己
But there are times when I can't control.
那你有没有为我们两母女想过？
Have you thought of me and our daughter?
自私
Selfish.
爸爸，你听妈妈的话，她就不会生气了
Daddy, mommy won't get angry if you listen to her.
乖，进房间睡觉吧
Good girl, go back to sleep.
去睡吧
Go to sleep.
快点睡觉吧， 吠甚么
You should sleep too, don't bark.
是谁？
Who's there?
阿港，你做甚么？
Kong, what are you doing here?
-这么晚了 ，有甚么事？  -回来跟你算帐
- It's late, what's it? - I came to teach you a lesson.
你喝醉了 ，有事明天再说吧
You're drunk, wait till tomorrow.
明甚么天
Why wait?
混蛋
Scum.
这一巴掌是还给你的
This is my revenge.
走开，我以后都不想再见到你
Go away, I don't want to see you again.
妈妈 ， 是我
Mommy, it's me.
甚么事？
What's it?
妈妈 ，爸爸和港叔叔在外面打架
Mommy, daddy is fighting with uncle Kong outside.
-阿胜…  -爸爸…
- Shing... - Daddy...
一人一次
One for each of us.
-阿胜，你怎么样？  -爸爸
- Shing, how are you? - Daddy.
阿港，你为甚么要这样做？
Kong, why did you do this?
这是我们两兄弟的事
This is our own affair.
现在都解决了
Now it's settled.
你别哭了 ，我没事
Don't cry, I'm all right.
我都说了你不用管我
I told you not to worry.
没事？看你的脸伤成这样
You're all right? Your face is seriously injured.
我陪你去华叔那里看看
Let's go to uncle wah.
都说了不用管我
I've told you not to worry.
你就听我一次行不行？
Can you listen to me just once?
爸爸， 听妈妈的话吧
Daddy, please listen to mommy.
你的脸都不知道有没有玻璃刺进去了
Maybe there's broken glass in the face.
不用了
No need.
不用？好吧，我找阿豪跟你去医院
No need? Fine, I'll get ho to take you to the hospital.
-老婆  -你怎么样？我扶你吧
- Honey. - How are you? Let me help you.
三更半夜，你就不要去麻烦别人了
It's late, don't bother him.
好吧…我跟你去
Okay... I'll go with you.
我早就说了 ，死性不改
I've told you but you never listen.
真是烂泥扶不上墙
You can never improve.
这真的不关我事
It's not my fault.
我也不想这样的 ，老婆
I don't want it either, honey.
不想你就退出吧
Why don't you quit then?
你每次出门 ，我都提心吊胆
I'm worried every time you go out.
好了 ，我答应你我不做了 ，行了吗？
Fine, I promise you I'll quit, okay?
你自己说的 ， 是你自己说不做的
You said it yourself that you'll quit.
-是啊  -女儿作证
- Yes. - Our daughter is our witness.
-好  -如果反悔你就死，不是， 是我死
- Yes. - You'll die, no, I'll die if you regret it.
真是的 ，大吉利是，乱说话
Don't talk nonsense.
-阿胜，你伤了骨  -喂？
- Shing, your bone is injured. - Hello?
-你最好去照x光  -喂？
- You'd better take an X-ray. - Hello?
是谁？
Who is this?
-阿豪吗？  -是的
- Is it ho? - Yes.
阿胜他说愿意脱离社团
Shing is willing to quit the society.
是吗？
Is it?
他亲口答应你吗？
He said it personally?
是呀，阿胜亲口答应的
Yes, he promised me personally.
帮我告诉胜哥，我很开心
Tell brother shing I'm happy for him.
还有， 阿嫂
And sister...
迟一点我找个律师让你们去美国
Soon I'll arrange for you to move to the us.
阿胜，阿豪说帮我们去美国
Shing, ho says he'll arrange for us to go to the us.
美国？
Us?
我和你都不懂英文，怎么过日子？
We can't speak english, how can we make a living?
也是
True.
但我们不会说英文
But we can't speak english.
我老婆能教你们 ，很容易的
My wife can teach you, it's easy.
阿豪老婆会教我们
Ho's wife will teach us.
谁？
Who's that?
你们是谁？
Who are you?
阿胜
Shing.
老婆，你怎么样？
Honey, how are you?
阿胜，照顾女儿…
Shing, take care of our daughter...
知道了 ，老婆
I will, honey.
-阿胜…  -先生
- Shing... - Mister.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
阿胜，你没事吧？
Shing, are you okay?
不要骚扰病人休息
Don't disturb the patient.
对了 ，炳叔， 是谁斩阿胜？
Uncle ping, who tried to kill shing?
一言难尽
It's hard to say.
弄熄香烟
Put out the cigarette.
我叫你弄熄香烟
Please put out the cigarette.
这里是医院，你以为是警局吗？
This is hospital, not police station.
真是麻烦
Annoying.
李先生
Mr Lee.
陈警官 ，阿胜怎么样？
Officer chan, how's shing?
他的脚筋被人挑断了 ，老婆当场死了
The tendon in his ankle was broken and his wife died on the spot.
你冷静点
Keep calm.
有些事情我还要问你
I have somthing ask to you.
陈警官 ，他在几号房间？
Officer chan, which ward is he in?
-这件事会不会是杨港做的？  -王八蛋
- Is it possible that yueng Kong did it? - Scum.
阿胜都敢斩？
How dare he tried to kill shing?
我不斩你我就不叫傻强
I'm not mad keung if I don't kill you.
走开，混蛋，给我走开
Go away, scum, go away.
阿强
Keung.
不可能，不可能是阿港做的
It's impossible that Kong did that.
李先生…
Mr Lee...
胜哥
Brother shing.
你怎么样？
How are you?
阿豪
Ho.
你为甚么要选我当办事人呢？
Why did you elect me to be the head?
很对不起
I'm so sorry.
不要紧
It's okay.
从我第一天出来混开始
From the day I became a triad member,
我已经预计了
I've seen this coming.
强哥，不要…
Brother keung, no...
不要拦我
Don't stop me.
不要这样
Don't do that.
你做甚么？
What do you want?
你做过甚么你自己知道
You should know.
-做甚么？  -我做过甚么？
- What do you want? - What have I done?
混蛋，你杀了阿胜两夫妇还不认？
Scum, you killed shing and his wife.
杀了你，混蛋，别跑
I must kill you, scum, don't run.
还跑？
Don't run.
走开
Go away.
别走
Don't go.
让开
Get out of my way.
砍死你，混蛋
I must kill you, scum.
还跑？
You run?
不关我的事，你疯了吗？
I didn't do it, are you crazy?
砍死你
I must kill you.
我只跟他空手打了一场  你为何冤枉我？
I merely fought with him, why did you accuse me?
走开
Go away.
混蛋
Bastard.
你做甚么
What do you want?
傻强，你别再来了 ， 否则我还手了
Mad keung, stop or I'll fight back.
还手？还呀
Fight back? Come on.
去死吧
Go to hell.
小心啊，大哥
Be careful, boss.
去死吧
Go to hell.
混蛋，去死
Scum, go to hell.
大嫂，你没事吧？
Are you all right?
要不要送你去医院？
Shall I take you to the hospital?
阿胜不是我杀的 ，你听见了吗？
I didn't kill shing. Do you hear that?
你明白吗…
Do you understand...
你傻了？
Are you retarded?
你不要再冤枉我，我不怕你
Don't ever accuse me, I don't fear you.
走
Go.
爸，现在洪兴没有人了
Dad, now hung hing has no leader.
很容易被人一次了结
It'll be easily taken over by others.
我躲在这里不行的
I can't just hide here.
就算我相信阿胜那次不是你做的
Even if I believe you didn't kill shing,
你以为阿强的手下会放过你吗？
do you think keung's men will let you go?
我才不怕他们
I'm not scared of them.
为何要生这么多事端？
Why did you create so much trouble?
现在洪兴乱成一团
Now hung hing is in a chaos.
想想办法岂不是更好？
We should find a way.
我尝试找五叔谈谈
I'll try to talk to uncle wu.
不行，这只老狐狸
No, he's a cunning old man.
你也知道他是做哪行的
You know him well.
找他只会让他祸害洪兴
He'll only bring hung hing down.
爸，反正要死，只能拼一拼了
Dad, we have to take the risk.
你也不希望我一辈子做喽啰吧
You don't want me to be like this forever, do you?
总之我觉得这件事不太妥
I'm not comfortable to do that.
爸，你怕甚么？我还小吗？
Dad, what are you afraid of? I'm no longer a kid.
这次就让我做决定吧
Let me decide this time.
周先生，他…
Mr chow, he...
怎么样，年轻人？
What's it, young man?
是不是码头那件事可以商量？
Is it time to talk about the business at the pier?
五叔，我想单独跟你谈
Uncle wu, I want to talk to you privately.
好啊
Sure.
-虾毛  -是
- Little ha. - Yes.
地盘的事你照我的意思去做就行了
Just do as I told you.
我知道了
Got it.
-你们先出去吧  -好
- You may leave first. - Okay.
你要自己跟进这件事，亲自处理
You must follow up and do it by yourself.
-我知道了  -就这样吧
- Got it. - That's it.
我先出去了
I'll leave first.
虾毛？杀死我龙头老大的那个？
Little ha? The one who killed my boss?
过去的事就别提了
Let bygones be bygones.
现在棺材绳、虾毛、广香堂他们
Now coffin rope, little ha and kwong heung hall...
都和我合作，只差你们洪兴
Are working with me, only left hung hing.
怎么样？
So?
葵涌的码头可以给我吗？
Can you give me kwai chung pier?
五叔，码头真的不能给你
Uncle wu, I can't give you the pier.
其他的都没问题
Any other is all right.
但其他的我没兴趣
But I'm not interested in others.
我只想要那个码头
I only want the pier.
五叔，我想你先关照我把洪兴处理好
Uncle wu, I hope you could help me get hung hing in order.
可以，有了码头甚么都可以商量
Sure, as long as I get the pier.
好，没问题
Okay, no problem.
不过每个月要一百万
But you need to pay one million every month.
我给你二百万
I'll give you two million.
下个月一号，半夜十二点
At midnight on the first day of next month,
你叫你们洪兴的人
send some men from hung hing,
在码头三号闸附近帮我做点事
and wait for me at gate 3.
引开警卫的注意力
Help me draw the guard's attention.
这很容易 ，我找两个手下处理
It's easy, I'll send two men there.
不行，我还要你亲自开一辆车
No, I want you to drive a car,
去码头里换一辆车出来
and exchange another car from the pier.
一定要你驾驶，其他人我信不过
It must be you as I don't trust others.
-为甚么？  -事成之后 ，我再给你五成
- Why? - I'll give you half a share after that.
五叔，你即是要我做替死鬼？
Uncle wu, you want me to be a scapegoat?
傻小子
Silly.
你被拘捕对我有甚么好处？
What's good to me if you're arrested?
我那批货，五成都不止二百万
My stuff is worth several millions.
你意下如何？
What do you think?
好，不过要先收一半的钱，即是一百万
Okay, but I must take a million as deposit.
还有，我只做一件事，就是这件事
And I'll only do one thing which is this.
好，就这样决定
Okay, it's decided.
五叔，我替洪兴社感谢你
Uncle wu, I thank you on behalf of hung hing.
既然现在大家合作了
Since we're working together,
我有些事情想问你
I want to ask you something.
-好啊  -谢胜两夫妇那件事
- Sure. - The case of tse shing couple...
和洪兴社弄成这样， 是不是你指使的？
And the current state of hung hing, did you plan it all?
不是我， 是他
Not me, it's him.
没错， 是我做的
Yes, I did it all.
是你们洪兴逼我这样做的
Hung hing made me do so.
还把我的眉毛剃了
You shaved off my eyebrows.
要怪就怪你当天不杀我
It's your fault that you didn't kill me.
我这样做是要给我的兄弟交待
I did that for my men.
不要这样…
Don't be like this...
何必这么冲动呢？
Take it easy.
我们是办大事的人
We're up for big business.
来， 回去休息一下吧
Come on, go home and rest.
来， 回去吧，走吧
Come, go home...
走吧…
Go...
阿绳，枪不是这样用的
Rope, guns shouldn't be used this way.
你一枪打死了他， 岂不是便宜了他？
Isn't it too easy for him to die this way?
你听我说吧，迟早会给他一点颜色看看
Listen to me, soon I'll show him my true color.
我玩玩他而已 ，五叔
I was just fooling him, uncle wu.
是就好了 ，你千万别破坏这件事就行
Okay, but don't ruin our business.
行了 ，我知道怎么做
I know.
阿豪，你可不可以…
Ho, can you...
炳叔，我不想管你们的事
Uncle ping, I don't want to be involved.
让我们回美国吧
Let us go back to the us.
阿豪
Ho.
周世年的为人你应该很清楚
You know chow sai lun well.
如果阿港和他有关系，肯定活不了
If Kong works with him, he'll surely die.
或者你跟他说说
Why don't you talk to him?
他看在你爸爸份上，也者会放过阿港
He might let Kong off for the sake of your father.
阿豪，你就当帮帮我吧
Ho, please do me a favor.
我现在甚么也不知道，怎样帮你？
I know nothing, how can I help?
你的车不能进来，停在一边吧
You can't get your car in, park aside.
请问五叔在吗？
Is uncle wu in?
在写字楼
In the office.
谢谢
Thanks.
五叔
Uncle wu.
-我可不可以替阿港求情？  -走开
- Can I ask a favor for Kong? - Go away.
你不用说了 ，阿港是心甘情愿的
No, Kong is willing to do so.
你有本事就收回他
Take him back if you can.
-五叔  -不要靠近
- Uncle wu. - Don't come near.
五叔…希望你看在我爸的份上
Uncle wu... for the sake of my father,
放过阿港一次吧
please let Kong go.
你爸爸？你爸爸甚么时候放过我了？
Your father? He had never let me go.
是他杀了你爸
He was the one who killed your father.
我不想他把你也杀了 ，傻小子
I don't want him to kill you too.
五叔
Uncle wu.
世侄，这个游戏不适合你玩
Nephew, this is not your game.
你玩不起
You're not up to it.
进去吧…快点
Go in... quick.
-爆炸了…  -着火了…
- It's exploded... - It's on fire...
快点…
Quick...
救火，快点…
Put out the fire, quick...
喂
Hey.
站住，别跑…
Stop, don't run...
去那边截住他
Block him from that way.
-不要动 ，站住…  -别动…
- Don't move, stop... - Don't move...
你告我甚么？
What are you charging me with?
打架不用判死刑吧？
I was just fighting.
小子，别太淡定
Kid, don't be too calm.
我的线人说你的车上有毒品
I was informed that there's drug in your car.
你这次不坐十年也要坐八年
You'll surely go to jail this time.
傻子，我早知道那老家伙会陷害我
Silly, I knew that old man would be trapping me.
我早就把东西丢了
I've thrown it away.
拉他过去
Pull him over.
走
Go.
站住
Stop.
不准动
Don't move.
长官 ，在车上搜到了这袋东西
Sir, I found this in the car.
长官
Sir.
我看这包不会是葡萄糖吧？
This isn't glucose, is it?
你陷害我？
You frame me?
进去
Get in.
-收队…快点  -收队
- Let's retreat... quick. - Retreat.
调头…快点
Turn back... quick.
怎么开车的？
What kind of driving is this?
-做甚么？  -甚么事…
What do you want? “What's it...
警官 ，阿港是无辜的 ，你们捉错人了
Sir, Kong is innocent, you arrested the wrong person.
我亲眼看见周世年的手下
I saw the men of chow sai lun...
栽赃嫁祸给杨港
Put it in Kong's car.
你以为你说了我就相信你吗？
You think I'll believe you?
我收到线报，而且车里真的有毒品
I received the news and indeed there's drug in the car.
你是洪兴的办事人，你当然会帮着他了
You're the head of hung hing, of course you'll side him.
长官…
Sir...
那些东西也要拿回去做科学鉴证的
The stuff has to be taken for test.
-阿港  -你为甚么经常帮着他们？
- Kong. - Why are you always helping them?
看他样子就知道他是贼了
I know he's thief when I first met him.
你是警察还是黑社会？
Are you a police or triad member?
他当然是黑社会
Of course he is a triad member.
你见过他拘捕黑社会的人吗？
Have you ever seen him arresting triad members?
你做甚么？
What are you doing?
你为甚么要这样害阿港？
Why did you frame Kong?
甚么？警官 ，你也听见了
What? Sir, you heard that.
要不要我跟你回去协助调查？
Do you need my help in the investigation?
周先生，这次很感谢你跟警方合作
Mr chow, thanks for your cooperation
才捉到这个匪徒
that led us to arrest this man.
别客气，我们做生意的
No worries, we as businessmen...
最怕的就是黑社会，我要感谢你才对
Fear triads the most. I should thank you.
你们这些人渣
You trash.
坐下
Sit down.
不要再来了 ， 当我还你人情
Don't ever come again, we're equal now.
以后别再让我看见你
Don't let me see you again.
不要乱来
Don't do that.
混蛋
Scum.
快点…追他
Quick... go after him.
上车追他
Get in the car and chase.
阿港…
Kong...
走，快走，来吧
Go, quick, come on.
上车
Get in the car.
阿港
Kong.
棺材绳在前面，别让他跑掉了
Coffin rope is in front, don't let him run away.
退后…
Move backwards...
棺材绳在前面
Coffin rope is in front.
有没有搞错，这样开车
How can you drive like this?
走开，老兄
Go away, man.
阿港，上车
Kong, get in the car.
你做甚么？
What do you want?
你搞甚么？
What are you doing?
撞他，撞死他
Knock him, knock him to death.
是他杀了你爸爸
He killed your father.
阿港，你怎么了？
Kong, how are you?
阿港
Kong.
我的脚…
My leg...
情况不妙，快走吧
Something's not right, let's go.
撞死他
Kill him.
不要那些货了
Forget about the stuff.
豪哥，走吧…快点走吧
Brother ho, let's go... quick.
警察就快到了
Police are almost here.
不要动…
Don't move...
起来
Get up.
快点，起来
Quick, get up.
走
Go.
我是洪兴的坐馆， 车是我开的
I'm the head of hung hing, I was the driver.
是我杀了他们两个
I killed them.
警官 ，不关他的事， 是我做的
Sir, not him, it was me.
-陈警官 ， 刚才那辆车是我开的  -要拉就拉我吧
- Officer chan, I was the driver. - Arrest me please.
-你们抓我吧  -是我杀了他们两个
- Arrest me. - I killed them both.
你们不要捉他，你们捉我吧
Don't arrest him, arrest me please.
是我做的
I did that.
-我告你甚么？  -是我杀了他们
- What should I charge you of? - I killed them.
-无牌驾驶吗？  -警官 ，那两个…
- Driving without license? - Sir, the two men...
-捉我吧  -拖车…
- Arrest me please. - Towing truck...
警官 ，可不可以给我一枝烟抽？
Sir, may I have a cigarette?
豪哥，你是一个好老大
Brother ho, you're a kind leader,
但不是一个厉害的黑社会
but not a good triad member.
上车，走吧
Get in, let's go.
老爸，对不起
Dad, I'm sorry.
我希望你会明白我为甚么这样做
I hope you'll understand why I did this.
我和你回美国
I'll go back with you to the states.
（剧终）
The end